Dominic di Furia

☑ dominicdifuria@gmail.com ② Guildford, Surrey ☐ +44 7595 024 663

domdifuria.pythonanywhere.com

Profile

I have a strong technical background with 6 years industrial experience in scripting, codeline management and delivering software solutions. In my current role I work closely with other departments in the business to deliver automated solutions to meet and improve their current work flows.

I enjoy problem solving and am constantly keen to learn and improve. While always taking pride in the work I deliver.

Education

2013 | University of Reading

2:1 MEng Robotics

2009 | Hazelwick School

A-Level - Electronics (A), Maths (C), Physics (C) 10 GCSEs (Grades A, B and C)

Skills

Technical

Python

Vue.js

Tcl

Bash

csh SQL

MongoDB

Proprietary Languages (Fidessa)

Proprietary Databases (Fidessa)

Regex

Tools

Review Board Rundeck Perforce

Operating Systems

Windows Linux

Personal

Problem Solving Debugging Self-Starter Communication Team Player

Work Experience

11/2014 - Present | Fidessa

🗒 01/2021 - Present | Developer

Working as part of a team that designs and develops internal software solutions to automate the work of the delivery and other development teams. This is to ensure as part of the CI/CD principles that software is produced and distributed using the same means.

Vue.js, Python, Tcl, Bash, csh, Rundeck, Perforce and Fidessa's proprietary DB is used for creating these applications.

11/2014 – 12/2020 | Delivery Engineer

Worked as part of a team that was responsible for the technical delivery and maintenance of Fidessa's multi-asset, sell-side trading platforms. On a managed, Software as a Service (SaaS) basis. The role included: building new customer systems; performing software upgrades; enabling new functionality and handling customer change and enhancement requests. The predominant languages used in these tasks is Tcl, SQL and Fidessa's proprietary language.

My secondary role was to help make tasks the department performed regularly as automated as possible. So I spent time coming up with new scripts and enhancing old ones to make our day to day jobs as quick and as efficient as possible. Python, MongoDB and Perforce were used to complete these tasks.

■ 07/2013 – 11/2014 | Advanced Roofing Services

Logistics Assistant

My role at this company is to help with the organising and setting up of sites, making sure the sites are safe and the materials arrive on time. My time here has taught me the value of teamwork and good communication skills.

2012 - 2013 | Total Hospitality

Waiter

Within this job I worked as part of a team, waiting on brides, grooms and their wedding guests ensuring they all enjoyed their day. Working part time here while in my final year of university helped me further develop my time management and prioritisation skills.

Awards

During my time at Fidessa I have received two awards:

- Commitment and Dedication
- Service / Excellence

Hobbies

- Snowboarding
- Breakdancing
- Climbing
- Cycling
- Running
- Cooking
- Video Games
- Travelling

Activities

Reading University Breakdance Society

- 2012 2013 | President
- 2011 2012 | Treasurer

During my time as the society's Treasurer and President I managed the society's finances, arranged training times and spots for our members and negotiated extra funding with the University for trips to a competition in Newcastle involving 20 people.

References

Available on Request